let's look at the answer to our quiz
we were asked which of these are true l1
capacity
is less than l2 capacity
this should be true
because the l2 cache
needs to have hits for things that were
l1 misses so if l2
has the same or lower capacity than l1
then not many things that miss in l1
will actually be hits in l2 and we want
the l2 to still have a lot of hits so
that things don't go
to even slower caches or even to memory
the l1 latency should it be less than l2
latency and the answer is yes
we look first in l1 cache
not because
it has a better
chance of finding the data than the l2
cache but because it has a lower hit
latency the number of accesses in level
one cache
is it lower than the number of accesses
to l2 cache
this is not true
all of the accesses loads and stores
go to l1 cache but only those that miss
in l1 cache
go to l2 cache so the l2 cache usually
has a lot fewer accesses
than l1
and finally l1 of sensitivity needs to
be equal to l2 associativity this is
potentially true but
usually it isn't
why well because the l1 cache needs to
have a low hit latency
and need not have the capacity of the l2
cache
similarly for associativity the l1 cache
because it needs to be fast
can have a lower associativity whereas
the l2 cache can be slower so we can
maybe afford a higher sensitivity so
typically that's what happens l one has
a lower associativity than l2 so this is
also not true